Mss.B.J35.Le
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Feb. 22, 1791; B J35Le.39; 7-1/2x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add.,end. Enc. Encloses copy of letter he sent to Dr. Smith concerning Franklin. For enclosure, see: Jefferson to Smith; Feb. 19, 1791.
  - Abstract of American travels, July 7, 1804; B J35Le.43; 10x8; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    D.in hand of J.Vaughan, translator. 8p. For original, see: Humboldt to J. Vaughan; [July 7, 1804], Misc.ms.col.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 5, 1805; B J35Le.41; 9-3/4x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end Enc. Encloses article by Annemours for Publication by the APS. Refers to Bartram. For enclosure, see: Annemours. Memoire sur le district ou Ouachita...; 1803. (see Explorations in the Louisiana country no.1.) Bur.of Rolls, vol. 6, 471-S, 2, v.83, 101.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 10, 1805; B J35Le.42; 10x8; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Rome, L. 2p. In hand of J.Vaughan. In French. Praises the U.S. Concerning his publications. Refers to Jefferson,
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Oct. 14, 1805; B J35Le.44; 9-1/2x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc. Encloses copy of letter from Humboldt. For enclosure, see: Humboldt to J. Vaughan; June 10, 1805.
  - Letter to [Caspar] Wistar, March 26, 1806; B J35Le.45; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc. Encloses letter from Tatham to the APS. Bureau of rolls,v.6,512-S.2, v.85,29. For enclosure see: Tatham to [Jefferson]; March 25, 1806.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H[ue] Girardin, Richmond, Oct. 31, 1809; B J35Le.1; 10x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Introduces his grandson, Thomas J. Randolph and outlines the studies which he should pursue.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, March 31, 1813; B J35Le.2; 8x5; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p.and add. Forwards seeds for gardening.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Jan. 9, 1814; B J35Le.3; 5x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p.and add. Is out of kitchen herbs. Forwards books. Refers to T.J. Randolph.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, May 1, 1814; B J35Le.4; 4-1/4x7; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. Sends seeds. Thanks for plants.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H[ue] Girardin, Richmond, July 2, 1814; B J35Le.5; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asks how much is due for books purchased. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, July 7, 1814; B J35Le.6; 6-3/4x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Lists books which he would like to purchase from his library.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Wirt, Aug.14, 1814; B J35Le.7; 5-1/2x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. 1p. Extract. Printed: Bergh, vol.14, 162; Ford, vol. 9, 465. Bur. of rolls,v.6,510-S.1, v.13,288. Enc. originally in letter from Jefferson to Girardin; Dec.13, 1814.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, Aug. 28, 1814; B J35Le.8; 10x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. Forwards publications, one of which was written by himself. Concerning the burning of Washington.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, Dec. 3, 1814; B J35Le.9; 10x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. Concerning Virginia history. Botanical news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, Dec. 13, 1814; B J35Le.10; 8x5; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. Enc. Concerning Virginia history. Refers to a letter he has written Wirt. For enclosure, see: Jefferson to Wirt; Aug. 14, 1814.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Dec. 21, 1814; B J35Le.11; 9x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning political parties in the US.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Jan. 20, 1815; B J35Le.12; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Returns cahiers and makes suggestions for improving the idioms, in re Virginia history.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 8, 1815; B J35Le.46; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Bur.of rolls, v.6, 471 - S.1, v.14, 16. Printed: APS Proceedings, v.87, no.3, 268.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, March 4, 1815; B J35Le.13; 5x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. Forwards reference tools for his use. Concerning the sale of his library and its shipment to Washington.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, March 12, 1815; B J35Le.14; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 5p.and add. Printed: Ford, v.2, 150; Bergh, v.14, 271; Philips. Girardin and Dufief...;p.11 Bur. of rolls, v.6,185-S.1,v.14,22.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, March 18, 1815; B J35Le.15; 5x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. Is working on his library, prior to shipment. Any help he can give on Virginia history is to be used as Girardin sees fit.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, March 27, 1815; B J35Le.16; 10x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Printed: Bergh, vol.14, 294; Philips, Girardin and Dufief...; p.16. Bur. of rolls, v.6, 185-S.1,v.14,29.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, April 14, 1815; B J35Le.17; 8x4-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. with initials. 1p.and add. Will read various letters pertaining to his history of Virginia. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Glenmore, April 22, 1815; B J35Le.18; 8x4-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. with initials. 1p.and add. Concerning history of the Revolution and incidents in Virginia history.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, May 12, 1815; B J35Le.19; 10x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning the capture of Richmond by Arnold during the Revolution.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Richmond, Oct. 21, 1815; B J35Le.20; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning the sale of his library. Refers to a microscope, Correa de Serra, and Gilmer. Concerning events in France.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H[ue] Girardin, Richmond, Dec. 25, 1815; B J35Le.21; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Concerning his desire for the culture of the grape in the U.S. Refers to D.Carr
  - Letter to [Peter Stephen] DuPonceau, Jan. 22, 1816; B J35Le.47; 9-1/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and end.: "referred to Historical Comm[itt]ee." For enclosure, see: B.Hawkins. Sketch of the Creek country... (970.3: H31).
  - Letter to [Joseph Francisco] Correa de Serra, April 26, 1816; B J35Le.59; 10x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Poplar Forest, A.L.S. 4p. Printed: Bergh,vol.15, 3; Thwaites, Lewis and Clark, vol.7, pt.2, 394.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Richmond, July 23, 1816; B J35Le.22; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Questions concerning Virginia history.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Richmond, July 31, 1816; B J35Le.23; 10x8-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter. Concern over his history of Virginia.
  - Letter to [Thomas] Jefferson, Oct. 10, 1816; B J35le.60; 9-1/2x8; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 5p.and end. Printed: Thwaites, Lewis and Clark, v.7, p.2, 397 (also facsim.). Enclosed originally in: Jefferson to DuPonceau;Nov.7, 1817,
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 26, 1817; B J35Le.48; 9-3/4x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning the Byrd account of the N.C.Va. boundary, in the APS. Bur.of rolls (under date of Jan. 16, 1817) v.6,134-S. 3,v.31,99.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, April 30, 1817; B J35Le.24; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning books. Concerning De Laage.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, June 17, 1817; B J35Le.25; 9-3/4x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Orders books. Received article respecting J.Q. Adams.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 28, 1817; B J35Le.61; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Bur.of rolls, v.6,472 - S.2,v.83, 127. Printed: Thwaites, Lewis and Clark, v.7,p.2,400 (also facsim.)
  - Letter to [Peter Stephen] DuPonceau, Nov. 6, 1817; B J35Le.49; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Concerning the Byrd manuscript on the N.C.-Va.boundary. Forwards document to the Historical committee on canal at Panama. Refers to Correa de Serra. Bur.of rolls, v.6,134-S.2,v.31,100. [Martin de la Bastide] For document forwarded, see: / Mémoire sur la possibilité...d' ouvrir un canal... pour communiquer de le mer Atlantique... a la mer Pacifique...; Paris, June 30, 1785 (386:M36).
  - Letter to [Peter Stephen] DuPonceau, Nov. 7, 1817; B J35Le.62; 10x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Enc. Printed: Bergh, vol. 15, 150; Thwaites, Lewis and Clark, v.7, pt. 2, 402. For enclosure, see: Clark to Jefferson; Oct. 10,1816
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 17, 1818; B J35Le.50; 10x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Concerning the Byrd manuscript of the N.C.-Va. boundary. Bur.of rolls,v.6,135-S.2,v.31,103.
  - Letter to [Peter Stephen] DuPonceau, Feb. 19, 1818; B J35Le.51; 9-3/4x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc. wanting. Encloses supplements for the Byrd manuscript of the N.C. - Va. boundary, in the APS. Bur.of rolls, v.6,135-S.2,v.31,104.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], March 10, 1818; B J35Le.26; 9-1/2x8; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning plants forwarded him in the name of Girardin.
  - Letter to William Tilghman, April 6, 1818; B J35Le.63; 10x8; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Concerning the deposit of the Lewis and Clark papers with the historical committee as requested by Clark and Jefferson.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, Dec. 26, 1818; B J35Le.27; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Forwards publication for translation. Comments on it. Concerning his health.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, March 8, 1819; B J35Le.28; 3-3/4x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Has written a letter to Chaudron, as he requested.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 14, 1819; B J35Le.52; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Thanks for APS Hist. and Lit. Comm's Proceedings. Glad of work on the Indinans. Bur. of rolls, v.6, 135-S.2,v.31,105.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Staunton, March 16, 1819; B J35Le.29; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Printed: Philips. Girardin and Dufief...; p. 24.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Staunton, March 31, 1819; B J35Le.30; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Wishes the son of J.W. Eppes to go to his school.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, May 10, 1819; B J35Le.31; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Printed (under date of May 11, 1819): Philips. Girardin and Dufief...; p.25.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Staunton, June 22, 1819; B J35Le.32; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Printed: Philips. Girardin and Durief...; p. 28.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, Sept. 22, 1819; B J35Le.33; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Printed: Philips. Girardin and Dufief...; p. 31.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, July 7, 1820; B J35Le.53; 9-1/2x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Enc. Encloses vocabulary of Nottoway tribe. Bur. of rolls, 6, 135-S.2, v.31, 106. For enc., see: Wood. Vocabulary...; March 4, 1820. (497.3:V85)
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Staunton, July 8, 1820; B J35Le.34; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Notifies him that a certain work has already been translated.
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Staunton, Aug. 26, 1820; B J35Le.35; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Printed: Philips. Girardin and Dufief...; p.41
  - Letter to L[ouis] H. Girardin, Baltimore, April 8, 1821; B J35Le.36; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Concerning his college. Concerning classical authors. Lists books.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Aug. 17, 1821; B J35Le.37; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. Concerning the University of Virginia. Concerning some of his intimate friends.
  - Letter to John Fry, Dec. 2, 1823; B J35Le.55; 10x8; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, L. 1p. Copy. Thanks for fossil. On same sheet as letter from Harry Toulmin to J. Vaughan; June 12, 1840.
  - Letter to [Louis Hue] Girardin, Baltimore, Dec. 19, 1823; B J35Le.38; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Printed: Philips. Girardin and Dufief...; p.49.
  - Obituary notice for Thomas Jefferson, July 14, 1825; B J35Le.57; Richmond enquirer.
    Two newspaper clippings pertaining to the death of Thomas Jefferson.
  - Letter to N[athaniel] Chapman, John Vaughan and Franklin Bache, July 18, 1826; B J35Le.56; 9-1/2x8; Randolph, Thomas Jefferson, 1792-1875
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. Enc. Concerning Jefferson. Forwards newspaper clippings about his death. For clippings, see: Obituary notices ...;July 14,1826
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 12, 1840; B J35Le.54; 10x8; Toulmin, Harry, 1766-1823
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Enc. Encloses copy of Jefferson letter. For enclosure, see: Jefferson to John Fry; Dec. 2, 1823.
  - Memorandum concerning the establishment of Fort Jefferson, etc., Undated; B J35Le.58; 7x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    by George Rogers Clark. A.D. 1p. Sent originally (?) to Louis Hue Girardin. 58.) Printed: Burk. History of Virginia; vol.IV, 371.
  - Memorandum on events pertaining to the Revolution., Oct. 10, Undated; B J35Le.11.5; 6-1/2x6-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.D. 1p.,on reverse of add.sheed, add.: Thomas Jefferson [dated] Sent originally(?) to L.H. Girardin. 11-1/2.) Printed: Burk. History of Virginia, vol.4,128-129.